icy-veins.com 2019-11-12

# Privacy Policy - Icy Veins

## Preamble

Icy Veins is legally owned and operated by VEDATIS SAS, a company registered in Lyon, France (registration number: 532 111 887 RCS Lyon), whose offices are located 7, rue Gustave Chamboeuf, 69100 Villeurbanne, France.

In practice, the site is owned and administered by Damien Thivolle and Vlad-Matei Mladin.

Icy Veins has always cared greatly about the privacy of our readers. We are aware of [the GDPR](http://data.consilium.europa.eu/doc/document/ST-5419-2016-INIT/en/pdf) (General Data Protection Regulation) that came into effect on May 25th, 2018, and it is our sincere desire to be in full compliance with these regulations.

On this page, you will find all the information related to user data, explained fully, and as clearly and plainly as possible. We regularly reference GDPR to better provide context to our stance.

## Data We Collect

The data we collect on you as an Icy Veins user depends on how you use the site. In this section, we will cover all the different types of personal data (as per the definition of GDPR) that we collect and explain why we collect it, while the sections below will explain how we use that data, how long we retain it for, and how you can access and modify it.

### Server Logs

The Icy Veins servers are hosted at [OVH](https://www.ovh.com/), which collects several pieces of information in their server logs: hour of connection, partial IP address (more on this below), page requests, etc. This information is collected from all users who access the site.

The IP address has the last 2 octets removed as soon as we receive it, thus providing anonymity, and making it so that, in reality, we do not see or store any actual, usable IP addresses in our logs. The remaining (first) part of the IP address is useful to us because it allows us, among other things, to observe the behaviour of the Google "bots" that crawl our pages, thus helping us improve our search engine optimization.

### Google Analytics

We use [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics) on Icy Veins in order to monitor our traffic. It consists in a javascript program, executed by your browser, that collects different types of non personal information and sends them to Google. From this data, traffic statistics are drawn up by Google Analytics, which we then have access to. The data Google Analytics collects includes:

  * Internet browser type and version;
  * previously browsed page (where you came to the site from);
  * hour of connection;
  * number of pages seen;
  * time spent on each page.

When we say that this information is non personal, we mean that it is impossible for us to correlate the behaviour of any given user that makes up the statistics of Google Analytics with the actual identity of a user. We have no way to access the raw information collected by Google Analytics, and can only view the statistics.

These statistics are vital to the short and long-term operation of the website, since without them we would be unable to evaluate which guides perform well, optimize search engine ranking visibility, and so on.

In terms of GDPR, Google Analytics is a "data processor", and they are obliged to make sure that they conform to the regulations, through their own privacy policy.

Furthermore, we have enabled IP masking (anonymization) in Google Analytics. You can read more about that [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2905384?hl=en), but in short it means that "Analytics removes the last octet of the user's IP address prior to its use and storage.", which should further alleviate privacy concerns and ensure that even less personal information about users is stored in general.

### Forum / Premium Accounts

If you create a forum account, you provide us with an e-mail address as part of the registration process.

Also, all forum users have their IP addresses logged by the forum software.

The e-mail addresses and IP addresses are only visible to the 2 aforementioned website administrators, as well as to Blainie and positiv2, the Icy Veins community managers and forum administrators.

If you use your forum account to create an Icy Veins [Premium subscription](https://www.icy-veins.com/forums/topic/32622-premium-faq/), then you also provide us with a first and last name as part of the Premium subscription process. This information is only visible to the 2 website administrators.

Payment information for Premium users is not collected or otherwise accessible to Icy Veins. All payments are done through [Braintree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/), a subsidiary of [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/), who are the ones who have access to this information, and who are obliged to comply with GDPR.

All third-party javascripts are disabled when using a Premium account (with the exception of external tools to provide game-specific tooltips, but these do not collect data), so they cannot collect any data from you at this time. Please note that this requires you to be logged into your Premium account when accessing the website.

On the sign-up page for Premium, we occasionally use [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/) to collect data on how our visitors use this page to try and improve it (to build heatmaps or poll visitors and ask them why they did not finish registration). See their [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy) for more information. In Hotjar's options, we asked not to collect location data during recording and to not send or record any of the fields where user can input sensitive information, such as credit card details. Hotjar is headquartered in the European Union and subject to GDPR.

### Communications

If you communicate with us, either through e-mail at one of the @icy-veins.com e-mail addresses or through forum private messaging, we may maintain a record of this communication. We also may maintain a record of the posts you make on our forums, including in comments.

## How We Use Your Data

In short, Icy Veins will never sell the information listed above to anyone.

We may share some of the information above either with the express consent of the user, or in one of the following scenarios.

  * when required to do so by law;
  * in order to defend our rights and interests in response to claims made against us;
  * when it is necessary to diagnose and repair technical issues on the website.

Forum user IP addresses are only used to be able to reasonably manage the forum community (enforcing bans on users who try to circumvent a ban by creating a new account, ensuring that we do not receive multiple contest entries from the same user, etc.).

Forum (and Premium) user e-mail addresses, as well as the first and last names of premium users, are never shared with anyone, and only used internally for the management of the forums and the Premium system.

We will never send you e-mails unless you specifically choose to opt in to such a feature, or unless we are legally obligated to do so (such as to notify you in case of a data breach).

## Data Retention

Forum account e-mail addresses are maintained for the duration of the existence of the account, and for **1 year** after that, while forum connection IP addresses and posting history is maintained for the duration of the existence of the account and, once the account is no longer active, for **1 year** from the time of posting. This last part is required by [French law](https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichTexte.do?cidTexte=JORFTEXT000023646013&categorieLien=id), to which we are subject.

First and last names of Premium users are maintained for the duration of the existence of the Premium subscription.

## Control Over Your Data

As part of our efforts to provide you with the required means to exercise your rights of **access, rectification, erasure, and restriction** , you can always e-mail us at [privacy@icy-veins.com](mailto:privacy@icy-veins.com) for any data-related matters.

This is also the e-mail address you should use if you wish to delete your forum account. Aside from this, the _User Control Panel_ of your forum account gives you ample control about the private information that you wish to share with us.

## How We Protect Your Information

The security of your information is important to us. Icy Veins implements safeguards to protect the information we collect. However, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe, such as choosing a strong password and keeping it private, as well as logging out of your user account, and closing your web browser when finished using Icy Veins on a shared or unsecured device.

## Advertisements

All the ads served on Icy Veins come through a third-party advertising company, [Enthusiast Gaming](http://enthusiastgaming.com/media/). When you first load our website, before any ads are displayed, you are presented with a consent form (from a "Content Management Platform", or CMP).

Depending on the consent you provide in this form, various pieces of information may be used in order to provide advertisements on this website, other sites, and other forms of media about goods and services that may be of interest to you. This information is collected from you through the use of cookies, and you can **withdraw your consent at any time by deleting the cookies from your Internet browser**. Once deleted, the consent form from the CMP will be displayed to you again when you visit Icy Veins the next time.

The CMP that we use belongs to Quantcast (you can see it [here](http://advertisingconsent.eu/iab-europe-transparency-consent-framework-list-of-registered-cmps/) listed on the website of the Interactive Advertising Bureau (IAB), an organization that develops industry standards, conducts research, and provides legal support for the online advertising industry). If you previously provided consent using Quantcast's CMP (such as on a different website that also uses it), those consent preferences will be used on Icy Veins, and you may not see the consent form when you load our website. If at any time you are unsure of your consent preferences with regards to our advertisements, we recommend deleting your browser's cookies.

It is important to reiterate that Icy Veins never has access to any of the data that may be collected by advertisements, with your consent, by Enthusiast Gaming.

## Cookies

Cookies are used on Icy Veins for registration, traffic analysis, and advertisement purposes. The Guardian has a very good article written about cookies and we encourage you to read it [here](https://www.theguardian.com/info/cookies), as we feel that it would be pointless to try and write something ourselves that would end up being far inferior.

## Children's Privacy

Icy Veins is not directed at or intended for children under the age of 13 (or under the applicable age limit, in such countries where there is a different limit). Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important to us, for that reason, we never knowingly collect or maintain information from children under the age limit.

Children under the age limit should not use our service, and if you are the parent or legal guardian of someone under the age limit, you are encouraged to contact us and we will delete any data on the child.

## Further Information

In conformity with French laws (article 23 of the law 78-17 from the 6th of January 1978, modified in 2004), the [CNIL](https://www.cnil.fr/en/) (French National Commission for Information Technology and Liberties) has been made aware of our user database and the nature of the data that we collect (declaration 1588056).

## Contact

For enquiries regarding our privacy policy, please use [ privacy@icy-veins.com](mailto:privacy@icy-veins.com).
